Jeffrey Green

Full-Stack Software Engineer | Finance Systems Analyst

Chicago, IL 708-979-5858

Email | Website | LinkedIn

Full-Stack Software Engineer with four years of professional experience in tech collaborating with multiple teams and departments. Strong creative and innovative problem solving skills. As a Software Engineer, I've grown a passion for building and maintaining applications with design and user experience at the forefront. Technology is an extension of the human organism and with that in mind, I strive to improve processes and find efficiencies for the good of the company, team, and the everyday user.

SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python
- Libraries/Frameworks: ¡Query, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, Numpy, Pandas, Django, Bootstrap, Bulma
- Tools/Technologies: Git/Github, REST/RESTful APIs, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Celigo, Postman, Heroku, Netlify
- Oracle Netsuite, Salesforce, PeopleSoft
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Microsoft Office / Google G Suite

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

GROUP PROJECT - ELON MUSK'S TWITTER

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Flexbox, Node.js, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Authentication, Heroku, Netlify

• Reverse engineered a full-stack web application that utilizes full CRUD operations and user authentication/ authorization enabling users to create an account, post tweets, and like/comment on any user's tweets.

SOLO PROJECT - EXPLORE MARVEL UNIVERSE

JavaScript, React, JSX, CSS, Flexbox, Responsive Design, RESTful API, MD5 Hash, Postman, Netlify

• Developed a modular and modern frontend React application fetching data from a third-party RESTful API.

SOLO PROJECT - CAR COLLECTOR APP

Python, Django, PostgreSQL, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bulma, Responsive Design, Authentication, Netlify

• Full-stack web application with Python servers and SQL databases built with the full-featured framework Django and styled with the CSS framework, Bulma.

EXPERIENCE

PEAK6 Chicago, IL

Finance Systems Analyst

Aug 2022 - Present

- Lead and manage projects for the finance team and be the liaison with our tech department and external consultants.
- Manage new systems integrations (banks, T&E, clearing firms, etc).
- Drive process improvements and automation by researching and testing new solutions.
- Work with FP&A on building reports and dashboards for business leaders.
- End to end management of customizations, including scoping, requirement gathering, solution, architecting, development, testing and deployment.

GENERAL ASSEMBLY Remote

Software Engineering Fellow

Mar 2022 - June 2022

- Full-time 420+ hours, 12-week program.
- Developed and deployed full-stack applications with in-demand technologies.
- Practiced version control and collaborative software development with Git and GitHub.
- Safely modeled and stored data in SQL and NoSQL databases.
- Consumed and integrated third-party application programming interfaces (APIs) in an application.

CARS

Chicago, IL

Digital Ad Production Specialist

Apr 2018 - Mar 2022

- Ensured customers' products are set live correctly and within turnaround time expectations by quickly and accurately inputting product and pricing data into online systems (PeopleSoft, Salesforce).
- Reviewed incoming contracts and enrollment documents for accuracy and compliance with standards.
- Worked with multiple partners in Operations, Finance, and Sales departments, handing off workflows for continuation & completion of enrollment.
- Thrived in a fast-paced environment, managing, keeping track of and progressing on multiple in-progress tasks.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp (June 2022)

ROCKFORD UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Business Administration (May 2016)